PHILLIP ZIWADA

CONTACT

Address: 25 Flower Street Carlisle

England CA1 2JW

Phone: +447425162423

Email: phillipziwadah@gmail.com

SKILLS

- Autonomous
- LAN debugging
- · Skilled in TCP/IP and WAN
- Desktop support
- Windows Server
- Technical documents comprehension
- Hardware upgrades
- · Application support
- Software diagnosis
- Application installations
- · Technical issues analysis
- · Staff education and training

CERTIFICATIONS

- Currently studying towards Cisco Certified Network Associate certification.
- Certified in Cybersecurity (ISC2)

LANGUAGES

English:

Fluent

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Detail-orientated and self-motivated individual with keen multitasking abilities. Confident in working independently, using initiative to complete tasks quickly, efficiently and with high degree of accuracy. IT engineer with strong network and system administration background and experience in programming and automation. Skilled in troubleshooting and problem-solving, focusing on maintaining high availability and performance of IT systems.

WORK HISTORY

Remote Support Engineer, 12/2023 to 09/2024 System IT - Carlisle, Cumbria

- Microsoft Windows Server including AD, DHCP, DNS & Group Policy Management.
- Microsoft Windows Desktop including Windows 10 & Windows 11.
- Active Directory & Azure Active Directory.
- Office 365 Administration including Exchange, Teams & Sharepoint.
- Networking (Switches/Firewalls/Routers/WIFI).
- · Microsoft Office Applications.
- · Virtualisation with Microsoft Hyper-V.
- MDM Mobile Device Management.
- Data Backup & Recovery Methods

IT Support Technician, 01/2020 to 02/2023 Siagon Solutions Pvt Ltd

- Installing and configuring computer hardware, software, systems, networks, printers and scanners.
- Configuring, updating and supporting field devices and field based users.
- · Planning and undertaking scheduled maintenance upgrades.
- Investigating, diagnosing and solving computer software and hardware faults.
- Repairing equipment and replacing parts.
- · Checking computer equipment for electrical safety.
- Maintaining records of software licences.
- Managing stocks of IT related equipment, consumables and other supplies.
- Ensure staff are aware of and comply with Network and system protocol and are informed of changes as appropriate.
- Liaise with IT Manager to ensure system integrity and disaster recovery plans are in place, maintained and tested.
- Liaise with the IT Manager on process changes and impact on IT needs especially where key operational activities are affected.
- Undertake regular audit of system use and produce and deliver training schedules to both office and field staff on IT systems use.

- Maintain all IT systems for optimum use and efficiency in accordance with policies.
- Maintain and manage security access to all systems
- Ensure appropriate data and system backup's are completed and logged.
- Ensure workstation and field device H&S requirements are reviewed annually and recorded in consultation with the H&S Representative.

IT Support Technician, 09/2017 to 12/2019 Prince Edward School

- Tackled projects with passion for web development combined with expertise in Python and Django.
- Tackled bugs by methodically eliminating software errors and implementing action to minimise future incidents.
- · Monitored technical performance of internal systems and escalated concerns.
- Managed databases with strong SQL skills.
- Guided and assisted users with technical issues, improving network performance and usability.
- Performed acceptance testing to deliver integration and interoperability of network technologies.
- Supported various operating systems and server technologies.
- Documented configurations and maintenance details in technical reports and diagrams.
- Configured routers, switches and firewalls to deploy and support LAN, WAN and wireless networks.
- Provided smooth communications by configuring LAN technology, wireless access points and controllers.
- Harnessed new technology to reduce error rates.

Junior Network Technician, 08/2015 to 08/2016 NamPak Pvt Ltd

- Conducted in-depth network reviews and tightened security policies to monitor access and prevent cyber threats.
- Reduced data loss with improved back-up and restoration processes.
- Maximised departmental efficiencies by creating and updating technical support documentation for systems and applications.
- Improved installation and configuration procedures to maintain stable traffic and response times.
- Monitored file servers and databases, improving network performance by 10%.
- Supported business continuity by developing, testing and implementing disaster recovery plans.
- Employed cybersecurity knowledge to establish stable connections and firewalls.
- Deployed and managed complex networks across broadband, Wi-Fi, LANs and VPNs.
- Evaluated latest innovations and adopted cost-effective, useful solutions.
- Completed reports detailing performance, costs and downtime issues.
- Reduced issue-resolution timeframes, minimising operational downtime and aiding company performance.
- Followed established SLAs, maintaining high IT quality-of-service levels.
- Requisitioned hardware and software to meet changing organisational needs.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science: Information Technology, 08/2012 – 05/2017 **Harare Institute of Technology** - Harare - Information Technology